

### PERSONAL INFORMATION

## Vasileios Tzivaras

- Yardamitsia, Filikis Etaireias, 45500 Ioannina (Greece)
- +306940361613
- xtzivaras@gmail.com
- http://vasilistzivaras.gr
- Skype billytziv | Linkedin linkedin.com/in/vtzivaras/ | Github github.com/billytziv

Date of birth 24/07/1990 | Nationality Greek

## PERSONAL STATEMENT

Tzivaras Vasileios is a graduate student of <u>Computer Science and Engineering</u> <u>Department</u> in University of Ioannina, Greece. For three years, he was the chairman of <u>IEEE University of Ioannina Student Branch</u>, where he created a working administration plan and carried out various complicated situations. Lastly, with all of his experience in personal IoT projects and his Bachelor Thesis about Drones, he became an Author in two technical books about <u>Drones</u> and <u>IoT</u>, which were published from Packt Publishing, Birmingham, UK.

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

### 10/02/2015-Present

# Web Designer, Developer and Author

Freelancer, Ioannina (Greece)

I have experience as a Web Designer and Author in the following websites:

- <u>networksgr.blogspot.gr</u> using Google blogger platform.
- entypwseis.gr and ieeesb.uoi.gr using Wordpress CMS platform.

## 02/06/2015-08/12/2017

## **Technical Book Author**

PACKT PUBLISHING, Birmingham (United Kingdom)

- Author of "Building a Quadcopter with Arduino" technical book with ISBN 9781785281846.
- Author of "Raspberry Pi Zero W Wireless Projects" technical book with ISBN 9781788290524.

### 13/06/2015-15/10/2015

### Software Developer

Greek Free Open Source Software Society, Ioannina (Greece)

Project coordinator of "Drone Lifeguard" which was developed within the Units of Excellence and successfully reached the semi-finals of Ennovation competition.

### 01/05/2011-04/03/2013

## Volunteer: Computer and Network Technician

Department of Computer Science and Engineering, University of Ioannina,, Ioannina (Greece)

- Laboratory equipment maintenance.
- Science and Engineering Department management assistant.

### 01/07/2012-01/10/2012

## Internship: Computer and Network Technician

University hospital of Ioannina, Ioannina (Greece)

Responsible for maintaining the network and fix any daily issues all across the hospital sections and project coordinator of a "Helpdesk" software.

- Local network administration
- Hospital LAN users administration



Curriculum vitae Vasileios Tzivaras

- Servers administration
- Extending LAN procedures
- HIS administration
- Emergency procedures
- HIS troubleshooting
- Asset management

## 06/09/2016-04/09/2017

## **Technical Book Reviewer**

Pakct Publishing, Birmingham (United Kingdom)

- Reviewer of "Internet of Things With Arduino Cookbook" with ISBN 9781785286582.
- Reviewer of "Building Smart Homes With Raspberry Pi Zero" with ISBN 9781786466952.
- Reviewer of "Intelligent IoT Projects in 7 Days" with ISBN 9781787286429.

### **EDUCATION AND TRAINING**

### 04/07/2009-30/02/2018

# Computer Science and Engineering Department

University of Ioannina, Ioannina (Greece)

Final grade: 6,8/10 Total ECTS: 300

## 03/02/2016-01/01/2018

# Quadcopter Landing Using Visual Servoing

B.Sc Thesis, Ioannina (Greece)

- Quadcopter Physical/Simulation Modeling
- Image Based Visual Servoing (IBVS)
- MATLAB

# PERSONAL SKILLS

# Mother tongue(s)

# Greek

# Foreign language(s)

UNDERSTANDING		SPEAKING		WRITING
Listening	Reading	Spoken interaction	Spoken production	
C2	C2	C2	C2	C2

English

Levels: A1 and A2: Basic user - B1 and B2: Independent user - C1 and C2: Proficient user Common European Framework of Reference for Languages

## Communication skills

- Communication and collaboration skills gained through IEEE UOI SB leadership role and CSE Department projects.
- Presentation and leadership skills gained through IEEE UOI SB, FOSSCOMM conference and Ennovation competition.
- Contact skills gained through my collaboration with PACKT Publishing, UK
- Deadlines, consistency, leadership skills...

## Organisational / managerial skills

- Chairman of the IEEE Student Branch at University of Ioannina, Greece.
- Responsible for software development at University Hospital of Ioannina, Greece.
- IoT team management through IEEE UOI Student Branch.
- Leadership role in workshops and seminars through IEEE UOI Student Branch, FOSSCOM and Ennovation competitions.





### Curriculum vitae

■ Taking initiative decisions

# Job-related skills

- Very good knowledge in C/C++, Java, Python.
- Very good knowledge in HTML, CSS, Apache administration, MySQL, PHP
- Good knowledge in Flight Controllers and Multicopter (Drone) assembly.
- Good knowledge in Internet of Things Applications (IoT).
- Risk management.

## Driving licence

В

## **ADDITIONAL INFORMATION**

## Memberships

- Chair of IEEE Student Branch at University of Ioannina.
- Member at Ubuntu launchpad.

## **Presentations**

The following topics have been presented in IEEE University of Ioannina Student Branch and took place in the Computer Science and Engineering Department:

- Introduction in Arduino
- Opensource software and Ubuntu installation
- Remote server access and file transfer
- Introduction in HTML5 and CSS3
- Website development with HTML5 and CSS3

I have also presented the project "Drone Lifeguard" at FOSSCOMM conference and Ennovation competition that both took place in Athens.